<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Michigan on Winds Howling</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/michigan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Michigan on Winds Howling</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:51:45 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/michigan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/favicon.ico</url>
      <title>Winds Howling</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Checking on the dead mall</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/lakeside-checkin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 15:51:45 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Justin</dc:creator>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/lakeside-checkin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I live right next to a big mall that closed a couple years ago: Lakeside Mall in Sterling Heights, Michigan. They have &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sterlingheights.gov/2069/Lakeside-City-Center&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;flashy plans&lt;/a&gt; to demolish it and erect a pedestrian-friendly, mixed-used utopia off one of the busiest highways in suburban Detroit. It could be a cool thing, or it could be another embarrassing attempt to inject &amp;ldquo;Main Street&amp;rdquo; into the car-centric sprawl. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to tell. After two years of hearing about it, nothing seems to be happening. I went over on my lunch break to monitor the situation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;figure style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/lakeside-checkin/lakeside-mall-snow.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;Snow from a winter storm is left to blanket the front entrance of Lakeside Mall, closed in 2024.&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;i&gt;Snow from a winter storm is left to blanket the front entrance of Lakeside Mall, closed in 2024.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I got there, a few Public Works trucks were parked outside, and guys in work gear were going into the mall. I asked what they were working on, and they said, &amp;ldquo;Water main.&amp;rdquo; Apparently the pipes froze; this was the end of the subzero stretch that was apparently named &amp;ldquo;Winter Storm Fern.&amp;rdquo; I asked if any of them knew when the mall would be demolished. &amp;ldquo;Your guess is as good as mine,&amp;rdquo; one said. &amp;ldquo;Probably by 2030.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mall formally closed in July 2024. Today, it&amp;rsquo;s entirely dark and locked down except for one store: JCPenney. I was a bit surprised to see another customer getting there at the same time I was. What are we both doing here? My surprise mounted as I wandered the store and spotted upwards of 10 more people spending their Monday noon hour thumbing through the racks. There were even more employees, and they all looked busy with something. Somebody was mopping the floor, somebody was processing returns, ladies behind the jewelry counters were asking if I needed anything, and people were out on the floor tidying well-stocked shelves. An entire &amp;ldquo;JCPenney Salon&amp;rdquo; appeared to be fully operational, with a receptionist scrolling on her phone. Least expected of all: &amp;ldquo;Now Hiring&amp;rdquo; signs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, the distinctly doomed vibe of a dead mall hung over everything. I have to imagine that a two-story department store in the throes of death probably looks pretty similar to one that&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;surprisingly busy, with upwards of 10 customers.&amp;rdquo; And can post-holiday price slashing really be the excuse for omnipresent clearance signs making it feel like half the store is 80% off?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/lakeside-checkin/jcpenney-barrier-to-the-rest-of-lakeside-mall.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;A transparent barrier inside JC Penney blocks access to the rest of Lakeside Mall.&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/lakeside-checkin/lakeside-mall-second-story-closed.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;The abandoned interior of Lakeside Mall, as seen from inside JC Penney.&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I asked one of the workers if she knew how much longer this store was going to be open. She replied confidently, “We’re stayin’.” I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if you could demolish an entire mall except for specific stores, but she seemed pretty sure JCPenney would somehow be spared the wrecking ball, along with what she referred to as “Sears.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lakeside Mall indeed had a Sears, but it &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macombdaily.com/2018/05/31/sears-at-lakeside-mall-to-close-this-fall/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;closed in 2018&lt;/a&gt;. I drove around the whole mall and couldn’t find anything that said &amp;ldquo;Sears&amp;rdquo; on it. I assumed she was referring to Sears Appliance Repair, which Google Maps shows to be an active business somewhere inside the mall. It has a phone number with a local area code, so I called it hoping to learn more about the business, but it only led to the following exchange with their &amp;ldquo;AI repair agent,&amp;rdquo; Samantha:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samantha:&lt;/strong&gt; Hi, I am Samantha, an AI virtual voice agent for Sears Home Services. How can I assist you today?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; I would like to speak with an employee.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samantha,&lt;/strong&gt; slightly peevish tone: Could you share a bit about why you would like to speak with an employee? I have access to the same information as any representative and can help resolve your issue quickly. What can I help you with today?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; I want to know more about the future of the physical location.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samantha:&lt;/strong&gt; I am here to help with scheduling appliance repairs and related services for Sears Home Services. For information about the future of physical store locations or corporate updates, please visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.searshomeservices.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.searshomeservices.com&lt;/a&gt;. Is there anything else I can assist you with regarding appliance repair or service appointments?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, I need to speak with an employee at the store. [pause] Hello? [pause] Hello? I need to speak with an employee.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samantha,&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;this is my final answer&amp;rdquo; tone: Live agents are not available. Your two options are to use our self-service website or continue with me here. Let me know how you would like to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hung up. So I haven&amp;rsquo;t figured out exactly what&amp;rsquo;s going on there. But there are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/SEARS/comments/1nqyrhn/the_sears_store_is_gone_from_montgomery_mall_but/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/SEARS/comments/1nqyrhn/the_sears_store_is_gone_from_montgomery_mall_but/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;threads&lt;/a&gt; about other dead malls with ghostly Sears operations allegedly taking place behind a thick veil of automated messages and AI. I called back a few hours later, and it was a whole different automated message system. No trace of Samantha, but still nothing helpful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oe2FxcWhCeo?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There might be news about Lakeside City Center buried in the city council minutes, but the most recent publicly reported information I can find about this project is that it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://metromodemedia.com/lakeside-closing/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;expected to break ground&lt;/a&gt; in late 2025. I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen any indication that it has. There was briefly a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.detroitnews.com/story/news/local/macomb-county/2025/02/10/owner-closed-sears-store-at-lakeside-sues-asks-judge-to-stop-demolition/78392729007/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;legal kerfuffle&lt;/a&gt; with the holding company that bought the empty Sears &amp;ndash; TL;DR: they said they weren&amp;rsquo;t consulted enough &amp;ndash; but that got &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macombdaily.com/2025/03/09/lakeside-lawsuits-dismissed-demolition-plans-back-on-track-for-closed-mall/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;worked out in March&lt;/a&gt;. The judge told all parties to work together in good faith to get the project done. The news is sparse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As it stands, JCPenney seems to be holding down the fort pretty well, and Lakeside Mall remains a reliable source for big, empty parking lots, friendly to flocks of Canadian geese in the summer and, in the winter, people doing donuts through the unplowed snow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>michigan</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grand Traverse Lighthouse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/grand-traverse-lighthouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 14:57:31 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:creator>Justin</dc:creator>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/grand-traverse-lighthouse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently paid my second visit to Grand Traverse Lighthouse on a chilly, overcast day in November. Unlike our first time here over the summer, the tower was climbable and the gift shop was open for business, so I was able to see much more of what the property has to offer. Here’s a rundown of the experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/grand-traverse-lighthouse/grand-traverse-lighthouse-and-sign-with-historical-dates.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;Grand Traverse Lighthouse with sign displaying significant dates in its history.&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/grand-traverse-lighthouse/grand-traverse-lighthouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;Grand Traverse Lighthouse&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This lighthouse is located at the tip of the Leelanau Peninsula, the “pinkie finger” of Michigan’s mitten-shaped Lower Peninsula. We drove up the east side of the Leelanau Peninsula, passing through the tiny beach towns of Suttons Bay and Northport before arriving at the big water of Lake Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/grand-traverse-lighthouse/map-of-path-from-traverse-city-to-grand-traverse-lighthouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;A map of the drive from Traverse City to Grand Traverse Lighthouse&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A short walk from the lighthouse deposits you on a rocky stretch of shoreline, possibly a nice place to hunt for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Petoskey_stone&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Petoskey stones&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/grand-traverse-lighthouse/lake-michigan-beach-at-grand-traverse-lighthouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;The beach at Grand Traverse Lighthouse&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For $8, we were allowed inside the lighthouse. The rooms were decorated to resemble the way they’d have looked between 1922 and 1938, when a large family called the McCormicks tended the light. Touchscreens were dotted around to supply information about the way they the McCormicks lived. According to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lighthousefriends.com/light.asp?ID=711&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lighthousefriends.com&lt;/a&gt;, one of the McCormick children was an important early member of the organization that now manages the lighthouse, which may explain their family’s starring role here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/grand-traverse-lighthouse/wooden-staircase-in-museum-at-grand-traverse-lighthouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;Cooking equipment in the kitchen at Grand Traverse Lighthouse&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After we paid our fee, we were left entirely to our own devices, free to consume at our leisure the shoddily edited, half-interesting fact sheets that are obligatory on the lighthouse circuit. From these I learned that the current two-story dwelling dates to 1858 and was the successor to a rather more dour-looking, free-standing brick tower built six years earlier. Some modernization work commenced in 1948, bringing upgraded plumbing, central heating and $3,500 of new furniture. However, lighthouses and modernity seldom mix; foreshadowing of obsolescence came in 1950 with the switch from a kerosene lamp to an electric light. The lighthouse said goodbye to its final keepers in 1972 and was revived as a museum in the ’80s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/grand-traverse-lighthouse/kitchen-table-in-museum-at-grand-traverse-lighthouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;Kitchen table at Grand Traverse Lighthouse&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/grand-traverse-lighthouse/pump-organ-in-museum-at-grand-traverse-lighthouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;Pump organ at Grand Traverse Lighthouse&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/grand-traverse-lighthouse/organ-in-museum-at-grand-traverse-lighthouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;Organ at Grand Traverse Lighthouse&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The museum was decent, but if you’ve been in an old-timey American house with lots of old-timey American stuff on display, there won’t be any surprises. What we were really interested in was getting to the top of the lighthouse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It took three staircases to get there. First, the wooden.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/grand-traverse-lighthouse/wooden-staircase-in-museum-at-grand-traverse-lighthouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;Wooden staircase at Grand Traverse Lighthouse&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After passing through a second floor packed with further lighthouse information, we ascended another set of stairs, this time metal and spiral.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/grand-traverse-lighthouse/spiral-staircase-in-museum-at-grand-traverse-lighthouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;Spiral staircase at Grand Traverse Lighthouse&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We arrived at a small landing with descriptions of local shipwrecks and went up one more twisting set of stairs into the lantern room.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/grand-traverse-lighthouse/staircase-to-top-of-grand-traverse-lighthouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;Staircase to the top of Grand Traverse Lighthouse&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There were no staff members at the top of the lighthouse, so we could sing and dance up there as much as we wanted to. We had plenty of room, because there is no longer any Fresnel lens. They had one on display downstairs, but it wasn’t the one used at this lighthouse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/grand-traverse-lighthouse/panorama-view-of-lake-michigan-from-top-of-grand-traverse-lighthouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;Labeled panorama of Lake Michgian from the top of Grand Traverse Lighthouse&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aside from the panoramic view, the coolest thing about the lantern room was that, along the bottom of each window pane, there were wooden boards painted to show the islands, bays and industrial plants that can be seen from up there — on a clear day, at least.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/grand-traverse-lighthouse/view-of-lake-michigan-from-top-grand-traverse-lighthouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;View of Lake Michigan from the top of Grand Traverse Lighthouse&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another thing to check out on the property is the “fog signal building.” This went up in 1899 to aid ships when it was too foggy to see the lighthouse. Its services ended in 1972, the same time they stopped having lighthouse keepers. An old brochure provides this bit of color:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Lighthouse inhabitants remember the fog signal as a heart stopping sound that sent them running deep inside the house to wait for the fog to lift.”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/grand-traverse-lighthouse/fog-signal-building-grand-traverse-lighthouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;Fog signal building at Grand Traverse Lighthouse&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was glad to visit the gift shop on the way out. Often the gift shops on our lighthouse adventures are closed, because they’re usually super small operations and we tend to show up at odd times. This one stocked a mixture of lighthouse souvenirs and basic supplies for a campground nearby, none of which interested me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/grand-traverse-lighthouse/outside-of-gift-shop-grand-traverse-lighthouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;Exterior of gift shop at Grand Traverse Lighthouse&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One item did catch my eye, though: a little bell that had the distinction of being the first piece of merchandise I’ve seen for America’s impending 250th birthday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/grand-traverse-lighthouse/america-250-bells-in-gift-shop-at-grand-traverse-lighthouse.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;America 250 bells in gift shop at Grand Traverse Lighthouse&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t help but see this as the first lapping wave of a flood of similar trinkets that will probably start cluttering store shelves soon. I’m partially looking forward to this kind of stuff, though — my personal favorite license plate is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:1976_Michigan_License_Plate.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Michigan license plate honoring the 1976 bicentennial&lt;/a&gt;, so hopefully some future classics will debut soon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ll finish with a sunnier photo from our first trip to this lighthouse, taken on July 12. We drove all the way from Detroit specifically to see it (and a few other lighthouses), camping that night at Arbutus Lake State Forest Campground and driving home the next day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/grand-traverse-lighthouse/grand-traverse-lighthouse-in-the-summer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lsquo;Grand Traverse Lighthouse in the summer&amp;rsquo;&#34; style=&#34;max-width: min(100%, 100%);&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <category>lighthouses</category><category>michigan</category><category>travel</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>